Hello friends, welcome to Mates.
In today's video, like us, I have brought another
very wonderful dividend
video for all of you. In this video, I am going to
tell you the complete details of a company
which will be one of the top 500 companies of India. This
company is going to be a subsidiary of III Group
and the name of this company
is going to be III Rd. Let's start this video
because in this video you will get to know
all the details related to dividend, import, dates, amount,
fund, but
before starting the video,
you should know the basic overview of the company. This
company will be seen working as a general private
insurance provider.
Now, what does the company provide you?
First of all, this
company provides you a wide range of
variety of goods including
auto,
health related, corporation
related, fire, personal accident, that is, whatever these different  I've
listed the names of
these companies here. They generally provide
you with all the insurance-related work.
Now, let's see
how old our company is. It's
almost 2021 years old, so it's a
well-known company. Most importantly,
it's a subsidiary of the ICICI Group.
Friends, let's now
look at the company's overview
so you can understand everything.
First, the company's name is ICICI
Lords, a banking and finance
company. It has been ranked among
India's top 10 companies in general insurance for quite some time.
The company is
listed on both the NSE and BSE. The
company announced its dividend on September 28th.
If many people don't know, I've
already made a short video for it.
If you want, you can go and watch it. The
ex-date and record date will be
October 27th, which will be an interim
dividend. The company's dividend and
percentage  The company hasn't announced it yet.
If you want, you'll
find a link in the description. You
can go there and check out the official details. If we
look at the company's dividend history,
you'll find the full dates and amounts listed.
This will tell you that the
company provides dividends twice a year, July and June.
July or October are two months in which the
company
provides dividends. Generally,
you'll see an amount between 45% and 55%.
This time too, you'll
see the same amount of dividend. Now, let's talk about whether a
company is fundamentally strong or not when we do fundamental analysis. The
first consideration is its market capitalization.
According to its market capitalization, this is a very good company worth
6434 crores. So, you
can consider this factor. Now, some of the
most important ratios are the P and
PB ratios.  If yes, then let me tell you that if we
talk about P ratio, it will
be 36.3 and if we talk about PB ratio, it will be 6.2,
debt to equity will be zero here, so it is a
very good thing, in 1 year the
company has given a return of 133.5 to all the investors, if we
talk about return on equity, it is
16.55, return on asset which is 3.13 will be
and if we talk about RO, it will be at 2.61, the
face value of every share of the company will
be ₹10 and with this the most important
thing comes that whether we should buy it
or not, so see this,
although it will be different for everyone individually
because this is an educational video, so I will
provide you a link in the description
www.fin.nic